When you are down and
drowning in your sorrow
Wish really hard
Look up at the sky
You are weak, oh so weak, but you can fly
If you can set yourself free...
AOKANA: Four Rhythm Across the Blue
Episode One:
"I'm Flying!
I'm Actually Flying!"
I haven't seen this sky in ten years.
I'm so envious.
It must be nice to have wings.
Boo hoo.
8:10...
It's touch and go.
It's gone!
I can't find it!
Help! It's gone, and I can't find it!
I'll be locked out of my house!
I can't believe I lost my
keys on my first day here!
I'm the worst! The absolute worst!
It's gone.
Good morning!
M-Morning.
So, you dropped your house keys?
How did you know?
Well...
I just heard you moaning over there.
If you like—
You'll help me look for them?
Thank you so much!
The people here really are nice.
Land of Compassion!                     Kamidori Island
Welcome to the
Four-Island Archipelago           Kasamatsu Island
Four-Island                  Kuna Island
Archipelago Map
Fukuru Island
"Ain't no need to worry. The Four-Island
Archipelago is the land of compassion!"
That's what my aunt said, and she was right!
I just moved here to Kuna Island yesterday.
Is this what you're looking for?
Thank you!
Thank you—
Masaya!
Ma—?
Whatcha doing?
A-A flying girl?!
Hey! You know you're not supposed
to land outside terminals.
Wow, amazing!
A girl just came flying from the sky!
Who's she?
Oh, I'm Kurashina Asuka!
Right...
Transfer student, apparently.
How do you know that?
Kurashina-san said it herself,
while looking for her house keys.
You even know my name?
Oh, right. I just introduced myself.
It's too early in the
morning to be so hypurr.
I'm Hinata Masaya.
That's Tobisawa Misaki.
We're both second-years at Kunahama High.
Me too!
Speaking of school, shouldn't
we get going already?
Kagami-sensei's on duty this week.
Oh, right!
Kagami-sensei?
She's the Health and P.E. teacher,
but she also does student counseling.
Anyone who's late is in for
some serious suffering.
Suffering?!
She'll expose their dark secrets, which
she collects via her intelligence web.
No way! That's not a very nice thing to do!
Come on, hurry up.
Let's fly.
There's a terminal over there.
Very well. Let's fly.
What about you, Masaya?
I'll run.
So, how do I fly?
You're wearing our school's uniform.
That means you must've been
briefed on Grav-Shoes.
"Grav-Shoes"?
Oh, you mean these?
I don't suppose you've ever used them before.
Nope!
Oh, well.
All right, pair up with me.
H-Hey, Misaki!
Surroundings all clear.
The stop light isn't on, either.
Okay, let's go.
Hurry up and grab on.
Right!
Come on, Masaya.
Fine.
Ready?
Yeah.
One, two...
Cleared fur takeoff!
Fly.
No! What is this?!
We'll crash and burn for sure!
We'll fall!
Don't fall asleep!
I'm awake.
So long as the Grav-Shoes are on,
we won't crash, no matter what.
R-Really?
Yeah. So relax, and enjoy
your stroll across the sky.
Amazing.
I'm flying...
It feels like these shoes can
take you wherever you want to go.
"Wherever you want to go," huh?
Kunahama Institute High School
Good morning!
Three minutes left!
How unusual for him to come flying.
Why do we have to run up this slope?!
Don't ask me!
Rules are rules!
Five...
Four...
Three...
Two...
Kunahama Institute High School
One...
Good.
No one's tardy today, either.
Well done.
Safe!
We made it!
Good morning, Kagami-sensei.
Morning.
Oh, so she's the strict
and terrifying teacher?
Hey, come on!
Why would you say that in front of her?!
Shh! Shh!
You're Kurashina,
the transfer student, right?
I'm the strict and terrifying Kagami Aoi.
Mind coming to the staff room with me?
S-Sure.
Nice to meet you!
Kurashina Asuka
I knew she'd join our class.
Kuna Island is where my dad was born,
so I've come here several
times when I was little.
But now, we've moved because of his job.
I was marveling at the pretty
ocean and vast sky here,
when I fell and dropped my keys—
For starters, take a seat.
Sorry about that.
The sky and ocean are visible
from the classroom, too!
Look, just sit down.
Oh, Tobisawa Misaki-san!
Thank you so much for earlier!
Get away.
You're in this class, too, Hinata Masaya-san?
Y-Yeah.
Kurashina Asuka
Perfect.
Tobisawa, Hinata,
you will be Kurashina's instructors.
Masaya!
We're off early today,
so it's already after school!
You don't have to tell me that.
At last, the day can truly begin!
What should I do? What should I eat?
I'm drowning in endless possibilities!
Is it just me, or is Tobisawa-san a
completely different person from this morning?
She has low blood pressure and is always
half-asleep in the morning,
so morning Misaki and afternoon Misaki
basically are different people.
As her friend, I find it a bit worrying.
I just live life true to myself.
Your attitude is almost
enviable at this point.
By the way, I'm Aoyagi Madoka.
Nice to meet you.
Kurashina-san, if you're free after this,
do you want to practice
using the Grav-Shoes?
Sure.
You're her instructor too,
Misaki, so come along.
Got it. I'll come fur sure!
Um, what do you mean, "instructor"?
The law states that beginners to Grav-Shoes
must be accompanied and
taught by instructors.
Misaki and I both had
to get instructor's licenses.
Then, then... You're my coaches, right?
I'm in your care, Coach!
S-Sure.
Misaki-senpai!
Mashiro.
I was on duty today, so I couldn't
come to school with you this morning.
I was so lonely!
Please let me get my fix on the way home.
Sorry, not today.
They made me her instructor.
Menacing
I understand.
Allow me to tag along.
I'm Arisaka Mashiro, of Class 1-A.
I'm Misaki-senpai's subordinate.
Or rather, her slave...
Something along those lines.
I-I see.
By the way, Kurashina-senpai.
Do you play games?
Do you have a PSQ? A 4DS?
Oh, could you be a mobile gamer?
Just so you know, anything goes for me.
What would you like to compete in?
Mind if I start explaining
Grav-Shoes already?
Feel free.
Gee, thanks.
Grav-Shoes—formally known
as Anti-Graviton Shoes—
came into existence after the discovery
of a mystery anti-gravity particle.
You know that much, right?
Yeah, Coach!
Land of Compassion!                     Kamidori Island
Welcome to the
Four-Island Archipelago           Kasamatsu Island
Four-Island                  Kuna Island
Archipelago Map
Fukuru Island
The Four-Island Archipelago is a special zone
where Grav-Shoes can be used to travel.
Students here have been permitted to fly
to school in them for a few years now.
Mew're boring me! That's enough
explaining, don't you think?
Okay, Coach!
Well, raise your heels
slightly off the ground.
Like this?
Yeah.
Now, when you're ready,
verbally command your shoes to fly.
They'll activate and rise
gently off the ground.
O-Okay.
One, two, three, and...
Fly!
It works! I'm floating!
I'm flying! I'm actually flying!
Kurashina-senpai seems
to be enjoying herself.
But...
If she flaps her arms around
that much, she'll start reeling.
I suddenly lost balance!
See?
H-Huh?
It's all good.
Safe landing technology
is built into Grav-Shoes, too.
R-Right...
This is how it usually goes at first.
I'm no good at all.
Okay, let's wrap it up for today
and go eat some udon!
Hey...
Udon?
Yep. The Four-Islands' specialty udon.
And I'm starving!
Sure. What topping will you get today?
What would be purrfect?
Sheesh.
We'll fly ahead.
Hurry up and join us, okay?
Got it.
Cleared fur take off!
Meow, too!
Oh, so your family runs this
udon restaurant, Arisaka-san.
Mashiro Udon
Whoa, flying fish!
I love them!
They use those flyers for the
stock here. It's delicious.
Flyers?
Until the udon gets here, let's have
a quiz on Kuna Island's Misaki-senpai!
Why?
Count me out.
Let's do it!
I want to get to you know you all better!
Here comes question one, then.
What is Misaki-san's favorite hobby?
Dunno.
Bzzt.
The answer is, "Making nukadoko pickling
beds, which she picked up from her grandma."
Moving on to question two.
What are Misaki-senpai's measurements?
Hey!
Mine plus 11-7-12!
How do you know that?
Here's your order!
Thanks as always.
No, thank you!
This looks amazing.
It's hot. Be careful
not to burn yer tongue.
Closed for Today - Mashiro Udon
Misaki-senpai, let's go
to school together tomorrow!
Okay, okay.
You two get on so well.
Well, see you tomorrow.
Thank you for today!
Tobisawa-san is so pretty when she flies.
On the other hand, I'm no good at all.
Don't let it bother you so much.
Little by little, you'll
get better with practice.
Uh, Kurashina-san...
You don't have to be depressed about it.
I'm upset.
R-Right.
Back then, when I took flight by myself,
It was so much fun.
But I immediately lost my balance and fell.
I'm pathetic.
So, please!
Give me the spartan treatment
starting tomorrow, Coach.
O-Okay...
Thank you!
I'm home!
Things aren't going so well.
I'm no good at all.
But...
Flying feels so great.
I can't wait for tomorrow.
Coach Tobisawa, Coach Hinata,
please teach me lots more.
Did someone move in next door—
Kunahama Institute High School
Man, I've meowver seen a beginner
be so bad at this before.
Kurashina-san!
Calm down!
Come on! You need to relax!
Okay! I will relax!
Uh, you're stiffening up instead.
How else am I supposed to—
She got swept away?!
No way!
We have to go after her!
She's such a troublemeowker.
She really is.
I'm totally no good at all.
Wait, what's with that posture?
For some reason, this makes me more stable.
Really...
She might just be a super-rare specimen.
What's that?
A street fight?
Doesn't look like it.
Let's go sneak a peek!
W-Wait for me!
You challenge me to a
match and lose right away?
How unseemly!
This is why I told you...
Satouin Reiko
Going up against me, Satouin Reiko,
is akin to taking on
a shark in the Pacific Ocean!
That analogy makes no sense, but damn it all!
Hey, that's Madoka's big brother.
What's going on? A duel?
Nobody at Kunahama can hold a
candle to me, Satouin, at Flying Circus.
Flying Circus?
A sport played using Grav-Shoes.
Wait, you've never heard of it?!
No...
Then, as promised, I shall take the
"In" in Kunahama Institute for myself.
Kunahama Institute
Kunahama Institute High School
Starting today, you're no
longer Kunahama Institute.
Kunahama stitute High School
Call yourselves "Kunahama Stitute" from now.
No! Anything but that!
What? Is our school going
to have its name changed?
Hold your horses.
Kurashina-senpai?
This is bad! The name "Kunahama
Stitute" would really suck!
No, look...
Come back to us!
Um, excuse me!
You idiot!
She spotted us!
Uh, I don't really get it,
but if I beat you at this
Flying Circus thing,
will you return the "In"?
Excuse me?
Who are you?
Why am I even hiding?
I'm Kurashina Asuka, and I transferred
into Kunahama yesterday!
A street fight! So exciting!
So you're challenging me to a match, correct?
Are you that confident in
your Flying Circus skills?
No, I only heard about it just now.
Today's also the first time I
flew using Grav-Shoes by myself.
Could you please stop with the jokes?
I'm not joking. I'm serious.
Very well.
If you're so insistent,
I accept your challenge.
What?
Thank you!
Wait, time out!
She's a Takafuji Academy student!
And Takafuji Academy is a
Flying Circus powerhouse.
Things are getting interesting.
Oh, come on.
Coach, teach me how to play Flying Circus.
Please.
Touch the 4 buoys floating     Time Limit 10m                    Buoy
above the water clockwise
Ocean
Shore
Player B
Player A
Flying Circus is usually
played above the ocean,
in a square playing area marked
by four buoys placed 300m apart.
Matches are one-on-one,
and the player who scores the
most points in ten minutes wins.
There are two ways to score points:
Scoring Methods
1. Touch Opponent's Back	       2. Touch the Buoys
Buoy
either by touching your opponent's back,
or by touching all four buoys in sequence.
So this actually is your first time?
Since you're a beginner, I'll drop
the number of buoys down to two.
The match will last five
minutes, half length.
If you score even a single point, you win.
Understood.
You'll be the referee, Shion-san.
O-Okay.
And you, be her second.
Who, me?
"Second"?
Someone who gives a player
advice from the ground.
I see.
In that case, Coach, I look forward
to your invaluable advice!
May my wings be covered
in the blessings of blue!
Don't just stand there.
You have to start from
the first buoy up there.
O-Oh, okay.
Here I go. Fly!
Will she be okay?
Beats me.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Let's begin!
Get ready...
Set!
There's one point, for starters.
Point scored by Satouin!
H-Huh?
Hey! What the hell is going on here?
A match, obviously.
What?!
K-Kurashina-san...
That's a Takafuji Academy student!
Is she wearing competition Grav-Shoes?
Why is she taking on someone like that?
She went and accepted a
challenge nobody made to her.
What? That doesn't make any sense.
I know, right?
Misaki, let me take over as second.
Sure.
Kurashina-san, do you hear me?
Huh? Y-Yes.
Coach Hinata...
First, look to block off the opponent's path.
Spread your arms, like a soccer goalkeeper.
L-Like this?
Do you honestly believe you can
stop me with a defense like that?
H-Here she comes!
Use a feint to create an opening,
and then touch her back!
Just circle around to her back and touch it!
Her back, right?
There!
Satouin has two points!
On top having no idea
how to play Flying Circus,
you also can't even fly properly?
You insult me just by trying to take me on!
Satouin has nine points.
The score is 9-0.
It was impossible after all, huh?
She doesn't seem at all
likely to score a point.
Well, then. Here I come
to score my tenth point.
Why don't you give up already?
I'll never give up!
I have to protect the "In"
in Kunahama Institute!
I'm going to score a point, no matter what!
She doesn't like to lose, eh?
Kurashina-san.
Y-Yes?
Do exactly as I say from now on.
Okay, got it.
What might you be whispering about?
Ready or not, here I come!
Now! Close your legs!
Then ascend like you're
doing a backward somersault!
Oh, my.
Are you going to honor my
triumphant return with an arch?
There!
Go!
I'll have your back!
Not so fast!
She dodged it!
Down to ten seconds left!
Is this it?
You are weak, oh so weak, but you can fly
If you can set
yourself free...
An air kick turn?!
N-No way!
I-I did it!
I scored a point!
P-Point scored by, uh...
Kurashina Asuka!
To Be Continued
Preview
I won!
And here I thought he had
no desire to go back.
I...
Udon?!
Episode Two:
"Udon...?"
Extra large!